Masquerades of Research is a drama film directed by Padraig Robinson.
The two-part feature film 'Masquerades of Research: Part I and II' is a fictional biography of pre-queer sociologist
Laud Humphreys, author of the infamous book 'Tearoom Trade: Impersonal Sex in Public Places' (1970, 1975).
Part I begins in St.
Louis in 1967 in a pre-Stonewall and pre-Watergate USA, exploring the impetus behind Humphreys “Sociologist as Voyeur” research method — a still radical
gesture and one of the first in the Western canon to turn the ethnographic gaze back onto the hypocritical conservative mindset that created it.
Why can’t statistics be avant-garde?
Part II begins in his Californian office in 1975, where we find Humphreys sweating in a
radically different USA on the cusp of republishing 'Tearoom Trade'.
Its relevance to contemporary discussions of intimacy, social presentation and data control is delicately
carried by visual intensities and rich performances that keep as many secrets as they give away.
Masquerade (Russian: Маскарад) was written by Aram Khachaturian in 1941 as incidental
music for a production of Mikhail Lermontov's play of the same name.
He turned it into a suite with five movements for an orchestra in 1944.
It is best known for the Waltz, widely considered one of Khachaturian's finest and most
popular pieces, second in popularity only to "Sabre Dance" from the ballet Gayane.